-宝贝儿  -知道吗
- Baby - You know,
大多数人去那是为了木屋和毛毯
Most people go for the hardwood or carpeting.
我觉得吉他和垃圾是一类玩意儿
I think guitars and garbage work just as well.
昨晚突然起了兴致弹吉他
Got the urge to play last night.
他们都回来我的部门了
Had to go all the way back to my apartment.
看来我以后得悠着点了
Thought I'd save on future trips.
你还真环保啊
Hmm. It's very eco-friendly of you.
来减排一下噪声污染怎样
How about keeping down on the noise pollution?
6点33分  你该起床刷牙了
6:33. You should be flossing by now.
我今天不上班
I'm not going to work today.
去打猎
I'm going hunting.
我睡着了再弹
After I sleep in.
又到了一年的那个时间吗
Is it that time of year again?
他是个自负的混蛋
He's a self-important jerk.
他是我的朋友
He's my friend.
他是个自负的混蛋
He's a self-important jerk.
貌似是我喜欢的白痴
Seems to be what I'm attracted to.
这家伙叫你吉姆  他甚至不知道你姓甚名谁
Guy calls you Jim. Doesn't even know your name.
吉姆是詹姆斯的昵称
Jim is short for James.
现在请出去  莱姆
Now go away, Lim.
打得好  吉姆
Nice shot, Jim.
还好  我瞄的是那棵树
Oh, yeah. I nailed that tree.
中午吃枫糖浆吧
Maple syrup for dinner.
我们应该带个导游来
We should have got a guide.
如果带人来指手画脚的
Oh, doesn't count as new adventure
就不算是真正意义上的探险了
If you have someone holding your hand.
另一方面  我们拿着武器
On the other hand, we are holding weapons
却不知道该干什么
And have no idea what we're doing.
-有意思  -我们得偷偷接近它们
- Fun. - Well, we need to sneak up on them.
我记得从哪看到过  印第安人说
I read somewhere that the native Americans say
火鸡知道你是怎么想的
Turkeys know what you're thinking.
那我还是别想德国黄段子了
So I should stop thinking about German porn.
不  不  那个会引得他们靠近些
No, no. That'll lure them closer.
咱俩还真不在行
We're terrible at this.
是啊  至少这里很冷  我的靴子还漏了
Yeah. Well, at least it's cold and my new boots leak.
时间差不多到了
Well, it's almost time anyway.
你带那袋子来了吗
Did you bring the bag?
3月30日  2004年
May 30, 2004.
上午10点7分
10:07 A.M.
威尔森医生通知我
Dr. Wilson informed me
如果治疗失败
That if treatment didn't go well,
我的白血病就只能让我再活6个月
My leukemia would give me only six more months to live.
11月30日  2004年
November 30, 2004.
6个月后  我还没死
Six months later, I didn't die.
只要我还活着
As long as I am alive,
我就要找到新鲜刺激的方式来感谢你
I will find new and exciting ways to thank you
给了我又一年的生命
For giving me another year.
到现在  又过去了很久  很久
Now move very, very far
以至于我可以确信
Away from there so that I can be sure
明年我还可以继续谢你
And thank you again next year.
谢谢你  吉姆
Thanks, Jim.
好吧  来看看  还有多少火鸡能重来
All right, let's see how many more turkeys we can miss.
这次肯定行
Yeah, this will work.
-搞什么  -天哪
- What the hell? - God.
对不起  我不知道怎么回事
Sorry. I don't know what happened.
我的胳膊动不了
I can't move my arm.
是中风吗
Am I having a stroke?
我不知道
I don't know.
好消息
Good news.
脑部CT未显示有中风症状
Head ct doesn't show any signs of a stroke.
所以他会没事的  是吗
So he's gonna be okay, right?
我真不敢相信你五年内
I cannot believe how much you've grown up
长这么大了
In five years.
她...
She's...
她不是艾米丽
She's not Emily.
阿什莉  我女友
Ashley, my girlfriend.
新生活  新探险
New life, new adventures.
阿什莉  认识一下吉姆
Ashley, meet Jim.
很高兴认识你
It's good to meet you.
那这次他的胳膊
So this arm thing,
意味着他又要犯白血病吗
Does that mean his leukemia's back?
我检查过血球计数和红细胞形态
I checked blood counts and blood cell morphologies.
指标都正常
Everything is normal.
那么这些血液检查
So these blood tests,
都能肯定这不是癌症吗
It means it's not cancer for sure.
他说了我没事的
He said I'm fine.
那你觉得是什么
So what do you think it is?
应该是没什么的
Hopefully something innocuous.
我认识一个医生...
There's a doctor I can speak to who's great...
...对诊断病情非常在行
Who's great at diagnosing...
什么
What?
对不起  那个口疮
Sorry, that cold sore,
已经长了多久了
How long have you had that?
两周  非常抱歉
Um, two weeks. I'm sorry.
我接到电话很着急
I-I got the call.
没来得及遮瑕就来了
I didn't have time to cover it up.
那是什么  吉姆
What is it, Jim?
那种口疮是因某种病毒引起的
That cold sore is caused by a virus.
如果你们俩接吻
Assuming you guys kiss,
病毒会传染  感染到你的脊柱
The virus could transfer, infect your spine,
造成麻痹瘫痪
And cause the paralysis.
这种病成为横贯性脊髓炎
It's a disease called transverse myelitis.
这算好消息还是坏消息呢
And is that good news or bad news?
非常好的消息
It's great news.
我给你安排病房  开始阿昔洛韦治疗
I'll get you a room and start you on acyclovir.
我刚刚享受了豪斯式一刻
I just had a House moment.
诊断出是因口疮引起的横贯性脊髓炎
Diagnosed transverse myelitis from a cold sore.
够酷吧
How cool is that?
而且病人还很吃这一套 我之钟爱便在于此
Patients really eat that crap up. It's why I'm loved.
-我在这干吗  -超声波清晰
- What am I doing here? - Ultrasound is clear.
意思是他肯定没怀孕  对吧
Which means he's definitely not pregnant, right?
额滴神哪  疼死俺咧
Dios mio, mi estomago!
没发现胆结石
No gall stones.
可能是憩室炎
Could be diverticulitis.
你吃过籽类食品吗
Have you eaten any seeds?
我要加入你们  安东尼奥·阿奎勒
I'm joining you, Antonio Aguilar.
我们将在上帝的乐队里演奏
We'll play in god's mariachi band.
抽取血液
Draw some blood.
那个自负的混蛋得的不是
The self-important jerk does not have
横贯性脊髓炎
Transverse myelitis.
他得的是癌症
He's got cancer.
你怎么...
How do you even--
好  好  好
Okay.
估计我都敢为此打赌了
Maybe I paid the redhead down in records a few bucks
从你以往的表现来看
To cc me on all your cases.
病人死了  你可能又会极度伤心
A few patients die, you might get sad again.
进行一场结束职场生涯的演讲
Make a speech that would end your career.
坦白讲  我观察你很久了
Frankly, I'm stalking you for you.
抽个血要这么久吗
How long does a simple blood draw take?
-差不多好了  -抽完了
- Almost finished. - Well, when you're finished
还不算完  检测一下
Almost finishing it, test it.
型男大主厨用上帝之手开膛破肚
Mi estomago's ripped open by the hand of god.
他在放我的血
He spilled my blood.
意识模糊  精神错乱
Confusion. Delirium.
为什么这么快把上帝之手排除掉
Why rule out the hand of god so fast?
你哥们白细胞数很少
Your guy's low white count
而且右臂瘫痪  说明
And right arm paralysis equals a recurrence
他的白血病复发了
Of his leukemia.
很简单
Simple math.
你看过
Did you look past
这篇报告的第一页了吗
The first page of the file?
完全没发现白血病细胞
No aml cells anywhere.
我亲自做的血液检验
I did the blood smears myself.
还是癌症
It's still cancer.
想知道我怎么知道的吗
You know how I know?
他咨询的是肿瘤专家  而不是普通医生
He's got an oncologist for a doctor.
难道你神奇的白血病感应器
And your magical leukemia detector
比流动血细胞计数器还靠谱吗
Is more powerful than a flow cytometer?
我寻找斑马是因为其他医生
I look for zebras because other doctors
已经排除了其他所有马类
Rule out all the horses.
也就是说你是那种医生
In this case, you are those other doctors.
所以得不出我的诊断结果
You haven't earned a zebra.
-我赌100块  -你认真的吗
- 100 bucks. - Are you serious?
没人愿意诊断出自己的朋友得癌症
Look, friends don't diagnose friends with cancer.
我能理解
I get it.
你没办法让自己客观
Your problem is you're not objective.
你的关心影响了诊断
Your caring is clouding your diagnosis.
抛除主观感情
Just cut that out
你会是一个好医生的
And you could be a pretty decent doctor.
告诉我乳酸水平
Just give me the lactic acid level.
27.
就算你不说英语
The fact that you can't speak English
你也会对我要说的
Is not an excuse for you not being humiliated
感到丢脸
By what I'm about to say.
这也不能成为
It's also not an excuse for you not telling us
你癖好网球的借口
That you were a tennis pro.
你要是说了我们也就不用浪费时间了
If you had, we wouldn't have wasted our time.
塔克安顿好了吗
Is Tucker settling in?
好了  已经服用了一剂量的阿昔洛韦
Yeah. Already got his first dose of acyclovir.
不用担心
And don't worry,
我为他女朋友订了儿童餐
I ordered his girlfriend the kiddy meal.
去看下一个病人
Next patient on deck.
戴尔·克林顿  化疗第六天
Del Clinton. Day six of chemo.
他外孙们刚走
You just missed the grandkids.
没关系
Oh, that's all right.
上次他们来把我的领带都画花了
Last time they were here, they painted my tie.
你差不多可以回家了
You're almost ready to go home.
感觉还好吧
You feeling okay?
感觉像跑了四圈
I feel like I felt after the last four rounds.
肿瘤疼痛没有加重表示一切都好
In oncology, familiar pain means all is well.
所以没问题是吗
So that's good, right?
对
Yeah.
我听说杰西和兹克来看你了
I heard Jesse and Zeke were by earlier.
是啊
Yeah.
对不起  戴尔  我该走了
Sorry, Del, I gotta run.
他们怎么样
How are they doing?
他们很好
They...they're fine.
没有游戏破记录  成绩第一
No game-winning hits? No aced report cards?
参加校园剧之类的吗
No school plays?
我想没有
I guess not.
你该走了
I thought you had to go.
你觉得不开心吗
Are you depressed?
我得了癌症啊
I have cancer.
你早就得癌症了
You've had cancer for a long time.
但从来没影响过你吹嘘
It's never stopped you from bragging
你的外孙们
About the grandkids.
可能情绪比平时低落一些吧
I guess I'm feeling a little more down than usual.
意味着什么吗
Can you give me something?
是的  我本不想让你感到紧张
Yeah. I don't want you to get alarmed,
但是沮丧可能是
But sometimes depression can be a sign
并发症之类引起
That something else is going on.
我现在就去给你多安排几个测试
I'm just gonna order a couple of extra tests.
好吧
Okay?
-怎么了  -他的脚
- What's going on? - It's his foot now.
-没事  -有事
- It's nothing. - It's not nothing.
我的脚开始感到
I just started getting a little tingling feeling
有一点点刺痛
In my foot.
严重吗
Is that bad?
阿什利  没事的
Ashley, it's gonna be okay.
可能是脚麻木了
It might mean his foot fell asleep.
也可能没事
It might mean nothing.
可以让我们单独谈谈吗
Could you give us a few minutes?
什么  为什么不能跟我说
What...why can't you tell me?
因为你把他弄紧张了
Because you're making him nervous.
就一会儿好吗  亲爱的
Just give us a few minutes, okay, hon?
跟你之前的诊断结果不一样
Does this mean that it's not the disease
对不对
You thought it was?
我之前给你的药没有起作用
It means the medicine I gave you is not working.
可能要加强力度
I just might have to hit it harder.
我打算给你的治疗中加入三氮唑核苷
I'm going to add ribavirin to your treatment.
吉姆
Jim.
你确定这次不是复发
Are you sure that this isn't a recurrence?
原来你只是在阿什利面前扮坚强啊
So the brave face is just for Ashley.
她还年轻  胆子小
She's young. She's terrified.
-她没有心理准备  -不用担心
- She's not really equipped. - Don't worry.
如果你得了癌症
Once you've had cancer,
你最担心的就是复发  我明白了
Recurrence is your biggest fear. I get it.
我已经全面检查过了
I've looked at this thing every which way there is.
没有这回事
That's not what's happening here.
你能给我女儿打个电话让她过来吗
Can you call my daughter and ask her to come down?
你为什么不自己打呢
You can't do it?
我和阿什利在一起之后
She hasn't exactly been talking to me
她就没怎么和我说过话了
Since I got together with Ashley.
我很想她来
I'd really like her to be here.
可以
Of course.
你要看他病的有多严重
Exactly how serious does it have to be
再决定要不要来看他妈
To justify you coming to see your father?
不  对不起
No. I'm sorry.
我只是宁愿你后悔来了
I just... I'd rather you regretted coming
也不要后悔没来
Than regretted not coming.
谢谢你  艾米丽
Thanks, Emily.
塔克怎么样
How's Tucker?
他的私生活一团糟
Oh, well, he's made a mess of his personal life.
但身体没事  很快就会好了
But physically, I think he's gonna be fine.
横贯性脊髓炎
Transverse myelitis.
豪斯怎么说
What does House think?
怎么了
What is this?
豪斯是我的监工吗
Is House my overseer now?
医生医治自己的朋友
No, it's just not always a good idea
始终不是个好主意  仅此而已
For doctors to treat Their friends, that's all.
豪斯赌100块他得的是癌症
Well, House has got 100 bucks on cancer.
所以除非你想加入
So unless you want in on the action...
邦妮还在做房产经纪吗
Um, is Bonnie still a realtor?
据我所知还是
As far as I know.
你介意我打电话给她吗
Do you mind if I call her?
我正在找新的地方住
I'm, uh, looking for a new place.
我要和卢卡斯搬到一起了
I'm moving in with Lucas.
不是网球
It wasn't the tennis.
你要搬去和卢卡斯一起住
You're moving in with Lucas?
是的
Yes.
你和邦妮是朋友
You're Bonnie's friend.
你知道怎么联系她
You know how to reach her.
你不直接找她
And yet instead of calling her,
反而来要我许可
You come and seek my permission.
是希望得到我的祝福
You want my blessing,
换句话说是豪斯的祝福
And implicitly, House's blessing.
我不需要豪斯的祝福
I don't need House's blessing.
很好
Good.
他的胳膊什么时候可以再动
So when will he be able to move his arm again?
很快
Should be soon.
又开始抽烟了吗
Started smoking again?
没有
No.
是么意思  咳嗽表示很严重吗
What... what does that mean? Is it bad that he's coughing?
爸爸
Hi, Dad.
梅丽莎
Melissa
我不知道你会来
I didn't know you were coming.
威尔森医生打电话的时候
I was at mom's house
我在妈妈那儿
When doctor Wilson called.
如果觉得不舒服我可以离开
I can go if it's gonna be weird.
不  不  不要走  没事儿
No, no. Stay. It's fine.
最近好吗
How are you?
他没事吧
Is he okay?
没事的
Yeah. He's okay.
虽然我觉得咳嗽没关系
I'm not a big fan of this coughing though.
你就是阿什利吧
You must be Ashley.
你好
Hi.
你没事吧
Hey, are you okay?
是不是口疮引起的
Do you think this cold sore thing could've caused this?
不  无论什么
No. Whatever's causing this
都不止影响了他的神经
Is affecting more than his nerves.
这儿需要急救车
I need a crash cart in here!
你们是不是有个垂死的墨西哥低吟歌手
Don't you guys have a dying mexican crooner
-要去治疗吗  -他已经好了
- To attend to? - He isn't dying anymore.
我们发现他有狂吃爆米花的习惯
Found out he was on a popcorn diet.
一天吃十袋微波炉爆米花
Eating ten bags of microwave popcorn a day.
膨胀的烟气损伤了他的肺
Huffing the fumes scared his lungs.
哇  那  真是很奇怪
Wow, that's... very strange.
豪斯哪儿去了
Where's House?
正在表演他例行的"躲开卡迪
Performing his ritual "hiding from Cuddy
以免接到新的病人"的舞蹈
To avoid getting a new case" dance.
这是一种爵士风情的舞蹈
It's sort of a jazz-fusion type of thing.
他也许在停尸间吃午饭吧
He's probably eating lunch in the morgue.
-如果你着急找他我可以传呼他  -事实上
- I can page him to your office if you want. - Atually...
也许我单独跟你们谈谈会更好些
Maybe it would be better if I talked to you guys alone.
豪斯和我正在为一个病人打赌
House and I have a bet about one of my patients.
你们想让他输100块钱吗
You guys mind making him 100 bucks poorer?
一个43岁的男人  白血病刚刚得到复原
43-year-old male in remission from leukemia
现在左臂失去知觉  呼吸困难
Presents with left arm paralysis and trouble breathing.
我猜豪斯一定赌他的癌症复发了
I assume House's money is on cancer.
谢谢  这很有用
Thanks. That's very helpful.
硬膜下的血肿能够解释...
Subdural hematoma would explain--
CT已经把这种可能排除了
Ct ruled it out.
我曾以为是横贯性脊髓炎病毒感染 所以给他用了抗病毒药
I thought it was tm so I started him on antivirals,
可是他病情更严重了
But he got worse.
是细菌感染吗
Bacterial infection?
细菌传染应该感染得更快些
Bacteria would move much faster than this.
那他现在就应该死了
He'd be dead already.
是不是真菌呢
Could be fungal.
真菌感染能解释他的呼吸问题
Fungal infection would explain his breathing problem,
可是解释不了"胳膊动不了"的问题
But not his "unable to move his arm" problem.
事实上  如果是曲霉菌类真菌
Actually, if aspergillus fungus balls
在他的肺上生根然后扩散到脊柱
Took root in his lungs and spread to his spine,
那就可以解释他这两个症状了
It would explain both.
谢谢了
Thanks.
治疗过程包括在感染位置穿刺
The treatment involves riddling the infected area
附以有抗真菌药物的小药丸
With bb-sized pellets of antifungal meds.
我想你该不会是装上点12的子弹
I assume you don't just load up the 12-gauge
然后在我身上乱打一通吧
And pepper me with birdshot.
不  我们会用更仁慈的方法
No. We have a slightly more humane delivery system.
但是我们确实要把你的身体打开
But we do have to open you up.
也会有风险
There are risks.
你怎么想  亲爱的
What do you think, honey?
我...我不知道
I-I don't know.
我是说  手术是最好的治疗方案吗
I mean, is surgery really such a good idea?
他身体状况很差
He just seems so sick.
我只是...
I just--
你们应该采取最稳妥的办法
You should do whatever you think is best.
这是唯一治他病的办法吗
Is this the only way to go after this thing?
因为他病情恶化很快
Because of the rapid progression,
我觉得我们没有时间去试其他的办法
I don't think we have time to test or try ivs.
他的身体状况可以承受麻醉吗
And he's strong enough to endure anesthesia.
可以
Definitely.
我希望你能在手术现场
I want you there during the surgery.
当然
Of course.
那就做手术吧
You gotta do it.
那好  奇斯医生一会儿过来
Good. Dr. Chase will be in here soon
把你推到手术室去
To get you set for the O.R.
呼叫一下奇斯医生到塔克房间做手术准备
Page Dr. Chase to Tucker's room for a surgery consult.
你能不能给我--
And can you get me--
卡普维茨先生想跟您谈谈
Uh, Mr. Koplovitz wants to talk to you.
出了什么事吗
Is everything all right?
他想跟他的医生谈
He wanted to talk to his doctor,
而不是跟他医生的助手谈
Not his doctor's assistant.
还有  豪斯在找你呢
Oh, and House is looking for you.
-你怎么跟他说的  -我说你在门诊部
- What did you tell him?  - That you were in the clinic.
我想你有十分钟就够了
I figure that gives you about ten minutes.
这是卡普维茨先生的病历  快去吧
Here. Mr. Koplovitz's chart. Go.
你好  索尔
Hello, Saul.
我听说你找我
I heard you were looking for me.
我感觉很累
I'm very tired.
可我却睡不着
But I can't sleep.
今天是你的幸运日
Today's your lucky day.
刚好我是睡眠专家
I happen to be a sleep specialist.
谢谢你  医生
Thanks, doc.
嗨  你这家伙能给我点私人空间吗
Hey. Can a guy get a little privacy?
真是个不错的藏身之处啊
Nice hiding spot.
事实上  这儿很完美
Actually, it's perfect.
它让我躲开了卡迪又找到了你
It allows me to hide from Cuddy and find you.
她想要怎样
What did she want?
多亏你  她刚刚给塔克做了检查
She was checking up on Tucker thanks to you.
就这样吗
That's it?
你想知道什么  关于你吗
Like what? Something about you?
关于怎么说起你吗
Something you could interpret as being about you?
也许是个变位词
An anagram maybe?
如果你能找到另一个藏身之处就真是太好了
It'd be great if you could play hide and seek somewhere else.
-我的病人要--  -没问题
- My patient just--  - No problem.
给我你欠我的100块钱你就可以走了
Just give me the 100 bucks you owe me and I'm gone.
塔克不是癌症复发
Tucker doesn't have cancer.
他也不是
He doesn't have a ball of fungus
肺内真菌感染
In his lungs either.
下次你用我的团队的时候
Next time you want to use my team,
我建议你要给小费
I suggest you at least leave a tip.
我手术要迟到了
I'm late for surgery.
你的助手说你在这儿
Ah, your assistant said you'd be in here.
我和邦妮谈了
I talked to Bonnie.
我们出去说
Let's take this outside.
卡普维茨先生刚睡着
Mr. Koplovitz just got to sleep.
对不起  她给我们找了个特别棒的阁楼
Oh, sorry. She found us this fantastic loft.
-外面说吧  -其实那不止是个阁楼
- Outside. - I mean, it's not a loft really,
那更靠近市中心
It's just more urban.
不是说我多城市化  可毕竟我过去是的
Not that I'm urban, but I used to be.
有两个卧室  还有很美丽的风景
It's got two bedrooms. Got wonderful views.
那真是个好地方
It's a really great place.
手术大概要进行一个小时
Procedure should take about an hour.
我会全程监控
I'll be observing the entire time.
谢谢
Thanks.
也许如果你能跟阿什利在一起会更好些
Maybe it'd be better if you stayed with Ashley.
她比我更害怕
She's more scared than I am.
她
Well, she's...
在她这个年龄
At her age...
她不应该面对过多关于生与死的问题
She's not supposed to be dealing with issues of life and death.
我追她的时候怎么没考虑到这些呢
Wasn't what I was planning when I went after her.
你为什么要离开梅丽莎
Why did you leave Melissa?
我们很年轻就结婚了  我们
We got married young. We...
我也不清楚
I'm not sure.
现在没什么好说的
There's nothing to talk about.
我需要你给我找一个新的病人的时候
Why are you doing surgery when I need you
为什么你在做手术
Finding me a new case?
你不想要新病人
You don't want a new case.
哦  对
Oh, right.
假装我是来这找威尔森的
Guess I'm here for Wilson.
很显然你没有告诉我
Obviously you didn't tell me
卡迪要搬到卢卡斯那里去了
That Cuddy was moving in with Lucas
因为你在保护我吗
'cause you were protecting me.
因为我告诉过你我不反对他们在一起
Which is odd, since I told you
所以是不是很奇怪
That I'm fine with their relationship.
这很明显
So obviously,
你质疑这些假设
You question one of those assumptions
或者你逻辑思维有问题
Or you have an issue with logic.
对  你不在意他们约会
Yes, you're fine with them dating.
可是搬到一起住
But moving in together
完全就是另一个层面的问题了
Is a whole other level of commitment.
现在是21世纪  威尔森
This is the 21st century, Wilson.
我明白成年人相处的逻辑程序
I realize that the logical course of any adult relationship
有一天可能会上床
Could one day lead to fornication.
可是  她想买个阁楼的事
Although, the fact that she wants to buy a loft
也许可以说明他们的关系
Could actually mean that their relationship
没我想得那么正式
Is not as serious as I thought.
哦  天啊  豪斯
Oh, for god's sake, House,
别这么对自己
Don't do this to yourself.
那是一个阁楼
It's a loft.
跟开放式的生活来说
It has no deeper meaning
没什么深刻含义
Than open-space living arrangement.
如果你考虑到当她再次看到失去了的
If you bought into her diatribe
城里的小窝时  会怎样谴责
About rediscovering her lost city girl roots.
还有两个卧室
And two bedrooms.
让结婚许诺变得飘渺无比
It just reeks of commitment issues.
没错  但还得考虑她有个孩子
Yeah. Or she has a baby.
这是中年卡迪所面临的经典问题
This is classic mid-life Cuddy crisis.
这是她看待双座敞篷车的方式
This is her version of a two-seat convertible.
是的  显然你可以接受这点
Yeah, clearly you're fine with it.
威尔森  他的肺大面积受损
Wilson, he's got global lung damage.
就是说不是真菌所致  而是五氯酚肺炎
Means it's not fungal. It's PCP pneumonia.
很显然  什么东西
Obviously something
在破坏他的免疫系统
Is knocking out his immune system.
三种可能  艾滋病
Three options. HIV.
获得性免疫缺陷  或我的最爱  癌症
Acquired scid, or my personal favorite, cancer.
你肯定会三种都检测
I'm sure you'll test for all three.
62岁的非洲裔美国人
62-year-old African-American man
患有淋巴癌  现在处于缓解期
With lymphoma now in remission.
我做了CT扫描  在他的左肺上叶
I did a CT and found a small lesion
发现了一个小小的损伤
On the upper lobe of his left lung.
既然他正在缓解期
If he's in remission,
你干嘛还给他扫描呢
Why did you bother scanning him?
在一次例行检查中
During a routine follow-up,
我发现病人情绪很低落
I realized the patient was depressed.
真是重大发现啊
Wow. That's quite a call.
谢谢  诊断显示
Thanks. The treatment indicate--
哦  抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
我不知道你正在忙
I didn't realize you were in the middle of something.
这是会议室
It's a conference room
四周都是玻璃墙
With glass walls.
你觉得我会一个人呆在这儿
You thought I'd be alone?
你的病人得了癌症
Your patient has cancer.
不是那个家伙
Not that guy.
他可能也得了癌症
He probably also has cancer.
可能他也是你的朋友
And he's probably also your buddy.
我猜你会想知道
Thought you'd want to know.
因为那样你就欠我100美元
'cause you owe me 100 bucks.
你患了急性淋巴细胞白血病
You have acute lymphoblastic leukemia.
简称A.L.L.
A.L.L.
也就是说旧病复发啦
So it is a recurrence.
不  和那个不同  是另一种白血病
No. It's different. It's a second leukemia.
可能是五年前所做的化疗引起的
Probably caused by the chemotherapy we gave him five years ago.
所以你才没发现
That's why you didn't see it.
他们可能重新命名为讽刺性白血病
Maybe they can rename it ironic leukemia.
并不是没希望治好
This is not the end.
检测显示癌细胞只在脑部有
Tests show that the cancer is limited to your brain.
这是好消息
That's good news.
他脑部有癌细胞怎么会是好消息呢
How can cancer in his head be good news?
血脑屏障将脑部的血
The blood brain barrier separates
和身体里的血液隔开
The blood in your head from the blood in your body.
也就封锁住了癌细胞
Keeps the cancer bottled up.
我们可以进行治愈
We can go for a cure.
那告诉我 治愈的希望有多大
So give me the numbers. What are we looking at?
90%的希望能治愈
90% chance of cure.
是吗
Really?
万一我们是那不幸的10%呢
What if we're in the 10%?
那么病情会持续恶化
Steady decline.
还可以享受六个月的美好生活
But six months of a good quality life.
他还得再进行一次
Does he have to go through
-骨髓移植吗  -不需要
- Another bone marrow transplant? - No.
化疗
Chemotherapy.
只需用药物就行了
We can go at this with drugs alone.
什么时候开始治疗呢
When do we get started?
先通过外科手术植入分流器
We begin by surgically planting a shunt
然后再把药物放入脑部
So we can get the drugs directly into your brain.
我已经定好了手术室
I already booked the O.R.
你是唯一一个可以让癌症
You're the only one who can make cancer
听起来是好消息的医生
Sound like good news.
我们帮你移除癌细胞  你就可以出院了
We get it out of your head and you walk out of here
胳膊麻痹症没了  癌症也好了
Paralysis gone and cancer-free.
你还得签一份医疗授权书
We also need you to sign a health care proxy.
如果手术过程中出现意外
If something goes wrong in surgery,
得有人来替你做决定
Someone needs to be appointed to make decisions for you.
出现意外的可能有多大
What are the chances of that happening?
非常小
Very remote.
我想让梅丽莎当我的代理人
I think maybe Melissa should be my proxy.
-什么  -不
- What?  - No.
请让一下  豪斯的新病人
Coming through. House got a new case.
修改后的手术室安排表 抱歉  威尔森  和你的撞一块儿了
Revised O.R. Schedule. Sorry, wilson, had to bump you.
你的病人还没生命垂危
It's not like your guy's bleeding out of his eyes.
豪斯  你的病人也没有奄奄一息
House, your guy's not bleeding out of his eyes either.
安排手术室的护士  看来是他快不行了
The nurse who books the O.R. Thinks he is.
你的手术没我的紧急
Your case is no more urgent than mine.
是的  但你比我要有耐心的多
Yeah, but you're way more patient.
没关系
It's okay.
你们可以在准备区讨论一下
You can talk about the--the paperwork
文件的事情
In the prep area.
比起我来  你更信任她
You trust her more than me.
对于这件事  是的
About this, yes.
你一路都顺顺利利
You've been through the good stuff,
但梅丽莎经历了人间地狱 现在又回到我身边
But Melissa's been to hell and back with me.
她最能鼓舞我度过这个难关
She gives me the best shot of getting through this.
-你还爱着她  -别说傻话
- You still love her. - Don't be silly.
我爱你
I love you.
求你了
Please...
不要想太多好吗
Don't make this into more than it is.
-好了  有感觉吗  -没有
- Okay, anything?  - No.
-现在能感觉到吗  -不能
- Can you feel this?  - No.
-这里呢  -也没有
- How about here?  - No.
其他人呢
Where is everybody?
梅丽莎和艾米丽到楼下去
Melissa and Emily went downstairs
-买早餐了  -阿什利呢
- To get some breakfast. - Ashley?
她有工作
She had work to do.
我还以为她今天休假
I thought she was off today.
其实她是没事
Well, she didn't really have work to do.
只是她有点生气
She was just pissed
所以假装有工作要做
So she pretended to have work to do.
我让她这么做的
I let her pretend.
好吧
Okay.
动动手指试试
Move your fingers.
化疗没用
The chemo's not working.
是不是也意味着不是癌症吗
Does that mean it's not cancer?
不  是表明经过第一轮的化疗
No. It means the chemo from your first round of treatment
白血病产生了抵抗
Has made the leukemia resistant.
那我是那不能被治愈的10%了
So I'm in the 10% that don't get cured.
也可能不是
Maybe not.
我们刚从一个家伙的肺里取出一个螺丝钉
We just removed a screw from a guy's lung.
但奇怪的是他却没好起来
And the weird thing is he didn't get better.
知道那意味着什么吗
Any idea what that means?
意味着你没有听我说话
It means you're not listening to me.
错  意味着我在忽视你来表达观点
No. It means I'm ignoring you to make a point.
这两者是有区别的
There is a difference.
你说的太含蓄  太深奥了
The problem with that technique
我不知道你想说明什么
Is I have no idea what point you're making.
那就是你的想法不值得我回应
That your idea is implicitly not worth responding to.
将病人的化疗计量加倍是很愚蠢的做法
Doubling your patient's chemo dose is stupid.
该死  现在明确了吧
Damn. Now it's explicit.
那可以让癌细胞
It could swamp out the resistance
的抵抗力减弱
Of the cancer cells.
理论上是这样没错  但不会
The fact that it theoretically should work
让这个做法精明多少
Doesn't make it any less stupid.
当然会  你也肯定会这样做
Of course it does. It's exactly what you would do.
我是我  你是你
I'm me. You're you.
桌子就是桌子
And a table is a table.
而化疗是毒药
And chemo is poison.
双重化疗就是双倍毒药
And double chemo is double poison.
情况变糟的时候  我能应付
I can handle it when things go wrong.
你却不能
You can't.
情况可能会变得越来越糟
And things could go very, very wrong.
我能处理好
I can handle it.
听起来很危险嘛
Sounds pretty dangerous.
确实
It is.
你怎么想  梅尔
What do you think, Mel?
我觉得你应该问阿什利
I think you should call Ashley.
你是我的亲人
You're my family.
我很抱歉曾经忘记了这一点
I'm sorry I forgot that.
我认为你该试试
I think that you should try
只要能让我们团聚的更久一点
Whatever could keep you with us longer.
是啊
Yeah.
你瞧
Look.
我的手臂可以动了
I can move them.
嘿  谢谢
Hey! Thank you.
吉姆  怎么了
What is it, Jim?
我需要去做一些化验
I'm gonna need to run some tests.
表皮内水疱
Intraepidermal superficial bullae.
-可能是天孢疮  -也可能是上火
- Could be pemphigus. - Or it could be from the fire.
否则他就挂了
Either way, he's dead.
我们无法止住渗液渗出
We can't stop the oozing.
没关系
Don't care.
我来这儿是因为现在1:15了
I'm here because it's 1:15
而威尔森在12:45就开始做化验
And Wilson started testing at 12:45.
-这就意味着...  -癌细胞消失了
- Which means... - The cancer's gone.
可他将近一半的肝细胞死亡了
But over half his hepatocytes are dead.
仅在24小时之内吗
In only 24 hours?
他需要移植一个新肝
He needs a new liver.
我们往好处想想
Look on the bright side.
你可以发布关于本病例的研究报告
You can publish the results of this case study.
使得他人不重蹈覆辙
No one will ever double the dose again.
双倍剂量的化疗消灭了你的癌细胞
The double dose of chemo got rid of your cancer.
但同时也损害了你的肝
But it also trashed your liver.
如果找不到与你匹配的肝
If I don't find you a new liver,
那你就只能活24小时了
You've only got about 24 hours left.
我们现在能做什么吗
So what do we do now?
你父亲已位列等待肝移植候选人的首位
Your father's been moved to the top of the transplant list.
但我们现在唯一能做的就是等待
But all we really can do is wait.
就这些了吗  只能等待吗
That's it? We wait?
告诉我哪些是我能做的
Tell me something that I can do.
我很抱歉  梅尔
I'm sorry, Mel.
你和艾米丽与塔克的血型都不匹配
You and Emily don't Match Tuck's blood type.
阿什利也不匹配
And neither does Ashley.
所以活体捐赠是没希望了
So a live liver donation is out.
你们唯一能做的就是和现在一样
The best thing to do is just what you've been doing.
陪伴在他身边
Be together.
但愿他已经告诉你  你活不长了
Hope he already told you that you're gonna die.
否则我下面要说的话就会非常不合时宜
'Cause it's gonna make what I'm about to say a lot more relevant.
豪斯  我知道走廊里在下雨
House, I know it's raining out there in the hallway,
可是...我刚才在急诊室帮病人做测试
But... I was just in the ER testing my patient
他的自主神经性功能失调
For autonomic dysfunction.
只有这个部门的淋浴够大
It's the only department with a shower big enough
足以容纳整个小组和心脏监护仪
For the whole team, plus the cardiac monitors,
还有个我  算了  相关话题
Plus me. Anyway, relevant part,
就在我们推他出去的时候
We're just wheeling the guy out,
来了个急救
Trauma came in.
一辆摩托车撞墙上了
Motorcycle versus semi.
有多严重
How bad?
他不走运  不过你的肝挺走运
Bad for the motorcycle. Good for your liver.
血检结果显示匹配
Blood type's a match.
怎么没人呼我
Why wasn't I paged?
因为有个问题
Because there's a problem.
他不是器官捐赠者
No organ donor card.
死者的姐姐是直系亲属
Dead guy's sister is next of kin.
她拒绝捐赠
She's refusing to allow the donation.
-她在哪儿  -20分钟的路程
- Where is she?  - 20 minutes away.
当你得知弟弟的死讯后
How do you get the call that your brother's dead
你还会出门吗
And then run out the door?
哦哦哦  这到提醒了我
oh--oh--oh, that reminds me,
我要去取干洗的衣服
I-I had dry cleaning to pick up."
库迪房子买了没
Did Cuddy buy the place?
还没  怎么了
Not yet. You okay?
只是聊聊
Just making conversation.
你的话题比较无聊
Yours was getting boring.
你在打什么注意
What are you planning?
啥注意都没有
I'm not planning anything.
我不信
And I don't believe you.
你打算怎么惩罚她和卢卡斯谈恋爱
How are you gonna punish her for dating Lucas?
额  这是话题也开始变得无聊
Okay, now this conversation is getting boring.
-你真的没事吗  -不
- Are you really okay? - No!
我不好  一点也不好
I am not okay. Not even close.
看吧  你还是挺成熟的
Wow. Okay. See, that's very adult of you.
才不是呢
No, it isn't.
只是面对现实
It's just me accepting the fact
深知我已无能为力并往前看而已
That there's nothing I can do and moving on.
我想这就是我对成熟的定义
Which is, I think, the definition of adulthood.
要是这样的话  做孩子更开心一些
Well, if it is, being a kid is a lot more fun.
好戏上演了
Showtime.
我跟他已经很多年没说过话了
I didn't speak to him for years.
可当我父母去世后
But when my parents died,
在他们的葬礼上我们和好如初了
At their funeral, we made peace.
这一定是父母在天有灵
Our parents must've blessed it.
我认为你父母必然也希望他在人世间
And I'm sure they would want him to do good
弥留之际做回善事
With his last act in this world.
他们希望我们友好相处
They wanted us to be friends.
以前我们之间的联系不太紧密
Our relationship wasn't strong,
但是在逐渐密切
But it was growing.
如果我让你们亵渎他的遗体
If I allow you to defile his body,
这会有损于我们之间的纽带
It will destroy that bond.
整个平衡就会遭到破坏
The itai will be harmed.
可这将拯救我的病人的生命
It will save my patient's life.
如果我告诉你他还没死  你怎么想
What if I told you that he wasn't dead?
你的意思是我弟还活着吗
Are you saying my brother is still alive?
我说你是个笨蛋
I'm saying you're being an idiot.
但是我没时间说服你脱离你的信仰
But I don't have time to talk you out of your religion
因而我有责任给你一个建议
So I'm stuck with giving you a technicality
让你自己去判断孰是孰非
That will let you justify doing the right thing.
如果他生前打算做的最后一件事就是捐赠他的一部分肝  你怎么想呢
What if his last living act was to donate a part of his liver?
不是全部的肝
Not the whole thing,
只是一小块而已
Just one small piece.
我还是不会去亵渎遗体
Then I'm not defiling a dead body.
豪斯
House.
人生在世最后能做的一件善举
The last generous act of a living person.
豪斯  太晚了
House, it's too late.
他的肝已经开始衰竭了
The liver started to degrade.
已经不适合做移植了
It's no longer viable for transplant.
真是出好戏
Well played.
你的信仰刚杀了一个人
Religion just killed another person.
这不公平  吉姆
It's not fair, Jim.
你刚使得我们家庭团圆
You just helped me get my family back together.
我还没准备好
I'm--I'm not ready.
我本可以与他们多待六个月
I would've had six more months with them
如果你没有给我加倍化疗的话
If you hadn't given me that extra chemo.
可我现在连一天都活不了
Now I have less than one day.
我很抱歉  你我都深知这些风险
I'm sorry. We knew the risks.
我不想再次失去她们
I don't want to lose them again.
我也不能再次失去她们
I can't lose them again.
我们已经尽力了
There's nothing more we can do.
五年前那次我需要输血的时候
Five years ago, when I needed a transfusion,
你用的是你的血
You used your own blood.
我们血型一样
We have the same type.
这就意味着你可以捐一部分肝给我
Which means you can give me a part of your liver.
-我是你的医生  -可你也是我朋友啊
- I'm your doctor. - You're my friend.
因为你也是我的医生我就该死吗
Should I die because you're also my doctor?
-当然不是  -那成  你被解雇了
- Of course not. - Fine then. You're fired.
现在你仅仅是我的朋友了
Now you're just my friend.
你该做出正确的选择
Now you can do what's right.
塔克  这...
Tucker, it's...
我不能
I can't.
和鸽子姐妹[奇夫妻里的角色]约会去了吗
Late night with the pigeon sisters?
我可不想每天
Every now and again, I'd like to come home
一回家就受审
Without getting interrogated.
某人心情不好
Someone's cranky.
又晚归
And late.
你去哪里了
Where were you?
去喝了一杯
Just getting a drink.
怎么回事  怎么我的冷冻食品
What? Why are all my frozen dinners
要放在桌子上解冻
Thawing on the counter?
我得腾点地方放我的玛格丽塔果冻鸡尾酒
I needed room for my margarita jell-o shots.
我用试管代替了瓶子
I use test tubes as bottles
这样它们就和我的手杖有同样的形状
So they'll be shaped like my cane.
你有这么棒的酒友
Why'd you go out drinking alone
干嘛还出去自己喝闷酒呢
When you got such great company here?
塔克想让我捐我的肝脏给他
Tucker wants me to donate a lobe of my liver to him.
那你就去喝酒
And you were out drinking.
你真的在考虑这个吗
So you're actually considering this?
没错  我去把我的肝泡在酒精里
Yeah. I was out marinating my liver in alcohol
为移植做准备  没错
To get it ready for the transplant. Yeah.
你嘴上这么说
Your mouth says no,
但你脸上可悲的表情出卖了你
But your pathetic attempt at a deflection
你脸上写满了内疚
Has guilt written all over it.
是我的错  都是我的错
It's my fault. It is my fault!
我让他做的化疗太多了
I gave him too much chemo.
你治好了他的癌症
You cured his cancer.
-但在治疗的同时却把他推向死亡  -瞎说
- And killed him in the process. - Quibbles.
他患有并发症  是意料之中的事
He's had a predictable complication.
双重惊喜  屋漏偏逢连夜雨
Surprise. Bad things happen to people who are sick.
这不是你责任
Doesn't make you responsible.
不  不是法律责任的问题  是道德问题
Oh, no...not legally. Ethically.
-道德  -桌子就是桌子
- Ethically! - A table is a table.
别做个可怜虫  威尔森
Don't be a doormat, Wilson.
伙计  你...你肆意毁掉我的食物
Boy, you are...you willfully ruined my food
还霸占我的客厅
And have taken over my living room
其实你已经把我当可怜虫了
Because you already think I'm a doormat!
你听着
You know what...
你错了
You're wrong.
你给我收拾东西走人
You...clean up your stuff and get out.
你错了
You're wrong.
塔克怎么样了
How's Tucker?
没什么好转
Um, still not dancing.
但戴尔·克林顿的透视结果出来了
But scans came in on del clinton.
-是个好消息  -谢谢
- It's good news. - Thanks.
塔克要是情况变坏了  马上告诉我
Let me know as soon as Tucker takes a turn for the worse.
我想陪在他身边
I want to be there.
看到肺上部这个小店了吗
See that small spot at the top of the lung?
那是以前的  这是现在的
That was then. This is now.
小点不见了
Spot's gone.
-那个迷你点  是吗  -就是它
- That tiny little spot, huh? - Yeah.
不怎么明显是吧
It's not too impressive, is it?
就是那个小不点儿差点儿杀了我
That little dot could've killed me?
是啊
Yeah.
幸运地是  我们提早抓住它了
Fortunately, we caught it early.
会好起来的
It's gonna be okay.
太让我惊讶了
That's amazing.
你把这些都清除了  还没跟我孙子说
You got all this off me not talking about my grandkids.
谢谢  邦妮
Thanks, Bonnie.
我会继续耐心等待的
Just gonna have to sit tight for a while.
好的
Okay.
我给一个阁楼出了价
I put an offer on the loft.
卖家拒绝了我
Seller turned me down.
我的出价和3个月前同样规格的房子的
I offered exactly what a similar unit
成交价是一样的
Sold for three months ago.
我想捐我的肝给塔克
I want to donate a lobe of my liver to Tucker.
你疯了吗
That's insane.
我只是捐出一小部分...
I'm donating a small portion of...
你有上百位病人
You have hundreds of patients.
在捐完我所有多余的器官之前
And until I run out of excess organs,
我为什么不尽我所能地去帮助他们
Why shouldn't I do everything I can to help them?
因为你是个医生  不是捐赠者
Because you're a doctor, not a donor.
为什么让我做肿瘤科主任
Why did you make me the head of oncology?
不是因为你的器官最多
Not because you have the most organs.
你考虑周到  富有爱心
You're thoughtful, caring.
是啊  爱心
Yeah, caring.
在你衡量标准里是个优点  不是缺点
By your own criteria a strength and not a weakness.
这是因你的内疚而生的想法
This is coming out of guilt.
这是因友谊而生的
This is coming out of friendship.
我的朋友在死亡线边缘徘徊
I have a friend who's about to die.
而我有机会救他的命
And I have the opportunity to save his life.
好吧
Okay.
你可以叫我可怜虫  随你怎么看
Call me a doormat. Get it all out of your system...
但我要捐肝脏给他
But I'm doing it.
为何
Why?
他是我的朋友
He's my friend.
我也是你的朋友
I'm your friend.
想想我吃了那么多止疼片
All the pain pills I've taken.
要是我需要的肝呢
What if I need your liver?
对啊  我怎么能这么自私
Right. How selfish of me not to have considered
没考虑到你未来的潜在需求
Your possible future needs.
他们都病危了
They're all dying.
都是你的朋友
They're all your friends.
我不是来找你吵架的  豪斯
I'm not here for an argument, House.
不吵架  对啊  这里是12A办公室
No. Right. That's room 12A.
那你来这里干什么
So why are you here?
来确认我是不是叫了搬运车
Want to make sure that I called the moving van?
不是  手术在二小时后进行
No. The operation is in two hours,
我希望你能陪我度过
And I'd like you to be there with me.
不
No.
怎...为什么
What...why?
要是你不幸去世  我就孤独一人了
Because if you die, I'm alone.
谢谢  吉姆
Thanks, Jim.
感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
没什么可抱怨的  如果没有你
Can't complain considering if it weren't for you,
我已经在鬼门关走两回了
I'd be dead--twice.
-你呢  -我感觉不错
- You? - I feel good.
要把衣服送洗吗
Sending out your laundry?
我要去康复中心  在坎多纳市附近
Going to rehab. Some place up in Katonah.
在你的新房子附近  不挨着老房子
Up by your new house, not near your old house.
这样对阿什利方便一些
Easier on Ashley.
我明白了
I see.
之前我对于重组家庭很兴奋
I was thrilled to get the family back together
而且梅丽莎在危急关头是个好依靠
And Melissa's great in a crisis,
但是在病危时陪伴你的最佳伴侣
But the person you want when you're dying
不是现实生活时的最佳伴侣
Isn't the same as the person you want when you're living.
你好  吉姆
Hi, Jim.
实际上  我的名字是詹姆斯
Actually, it's James.
你终于承认他是以自我为中心的混蛋了吧
You ready to admit that he's a self-important jerk?
我不后悔做了捐献
I still feel good about what I did.
你不生气吗
You don't feel angry?
我是有点失望
Ah. I'm a little disappointed.
失望就是软柿子的生气方式
Disappointment is anger for wimps.
你不用一直做老好人
You don't have to be so gentle about everything.
偶尔生个气也没什么
It's okay to get angry once in a while.
你不能改变既定惯例
You can't change a table.
其实  你可以的
Actually, you can.
只需要一层漆和放手做的胆量
Just need a coat of paint and the guts to use it.
邦妮
Bonnie.
邦妮告诉我卡迪的出价
Bonnie told me what Cuddy bid.
你要出价高过她吗
You're gonna outbid her?
我们的确需要个更大的冰箱
We do need a bigger refrigerator.
她伤害了我的朋友  她该受到惩罚
She hurt my friend. She should be punished.
你生气了
You got mad.
我为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.
卡迪不会有同样想法的
Cuddy won't share that sentiment.
你打算怎么跟她解释
How are you going to explain it to her?
我去更新我们的私人邮箱地址
I'm changing our address to a p.o. Box.
她最终会发现的
She'll find out eventually.
过去的事情
A problem delayed
是没人追究的
Is a problem denied.
邦妮  这房子我要了
Bonnie. I'll take it.
慢慢来
Baby steps.